Samir Antoun Freitas Aniz

Software Engineer

Location: São Paulo, SP, Brazil | Phone: +55 11 93370-3313| Email: samiraniz.jar@gmail.com LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/samir-antoun-freitas-aniz | GitHub: github.com/Serious-Sam97

SUMMARY

Software Engineer with over 8 years of experience with a robust OOP and scripting background. Specialized in Software Development using TDD, BDD, and upholding software security at Turno and Avem. Quick to address complex technical issues, prioritize innovation and industry standards. Committed to driving technological advancements and eager to tackle challenging projects that make a significant impact.

SKILLS

Proficient: Software Development, Software Architecture, Code Optimization, Design Patterns, PHP, JavaScript, Vue.js, React.js, Linux, GIT, Testing, SQL, No SQL, SOA, Adaptability, Effective Communication, Problem-solving, Teamwork, TDD, BDD, CI/CD, Critical Thinking, MySQL, Postgres, Data Structures, Algorithms, SDLC, Clean Code, Java, Dot Net and Agile

Intermediate: CSS, C, C++, Solidity, Node.js and Python and AWS

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer

Thoughtworks, (Westchester, Illinois, United States) - Remote

12/2024

Core Responsibilities:

- Developed and integrated multiple microservices, ensuring robust communication (REST/gRPC) and scalable, resilient architectures.
- Established advanced observability practices using Datadog and Honeycomb, significantly reducing detection and resolution time for critical incidents.
- Automated CI/CD pipelines with Docker and GitHub Actions/Jenkins, enabling fast, reliable deployments and rigorous automated testing (TDD/BDD).
- Facilitated effective communication and knowledge sharing across service teams to synchronize efforts and align technical decisions.

Key Technologies and Tools: Java, Spring, React.js, JavaScript, Postgres, Slack, Microsoft Teams, Clean Architecture, TDD, BDD, CI/CD, Docker, GIT and Jira.

Senior Software Engineer

Cambridge, United Kingdom, UK – Remote

07/2024-12/2024

Core Responsibilities:

• Designed and implemented scalable distributed computing solutions leveraging Google Cloud Platform (GCP) resources for client-facing high-performance workloads.

Key Technologies and Tools: Python, Fast API, React.js, JavaScript, Google Cloud, MySQL, Slack, Solidity, TDD, BDD, CI/CD, Docker, GIT and Jira.

Senior Software Engineer

Turno, Hawaii, US – Remote

11/2020 - 07/2024

Core Responsibilities:

- Enhanced web application performance, resulting in a 70% boost in speed and user satisfaction.
- Improved backend efficiency of high-load, problematic API routes, resulting in an 80% faster response speed.
- Increased codebase test coverage from 70% to 100%, enhancing software reliability.
- Optimized database queries, resulting in a 80% reduction in server response times.
- Pioneered the optimization of backend processes, achieving faster response times and superior code quality.
- Revamped legacy codebase with clean code principles and design patterns, enhancing structure and maintainability.
- Implemented advanced security measures to protect against cyber threats and preserve data integrity.
- Create web applications based on the product timeline and business rules.

Key Technologies and Tools: PHP 8, Java, Vue.js 2, JavaScript, MySQL, Slack, Laravel, TDD, BDD, CI/CD, Docker, GIT and Jira.

Software Engineer

Adira, São Paulo, BR - On-site

01/2017 to 10/2020

Core Responsibilities:

- Create web applications based on the product timeline and business rules.
- Directed a team that successfully transitioned to Agile methodology, increasing sprint completion rates by 40%.
- Using Scrum in the project to control work effectively and efficiently, leveraging teams that work towards a common goal.
- Application management on AWS, to maintain a safe and low-cost environment.

Key Technologies and Tools: PHP 7, Dot Net, Laravel, TDD, JavaScript, Vue.js 2, GIT and Slack.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Computer Science

University Anhembi Morumbi, SP, Brazil

01/2016 to 12/2019

• Relevant coursework: Data Structures and Computer Architecture

CERTIFICATES/COURSES

BEHAVIOR DRIVEN DEVELOPMENT, Alura, Brazil	09/2020
PHP: CLEAN ARCHITECTURE, Alura, Brazil	09/2020
Test-driven development, Alura, Brazil	09/2020
DESIGN PATTERNS, Alura, Brazil	08/2020
SOLID, Alura, Brazil	08/2020
Scrum Foundation Professional Certificate (SFPC), CertiProf, Brazil	06/2020
Oracle Database Foundations Certified Junior Associate, Oracle, Brazil	06/2019

LANGUAGES

Portuguese: Native English: Fluent